<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<sst xmlns="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/spreadsheetml/2006/main" count="172" uniqueCount="120"><si><t>Metadata for file "checklist_names.txt"</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="11"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Calibri"/><family val="2"/><scheme val="minor"/></rPr><t>Note:</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="11"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Calibri"/><family val="2"/><scheme val="minor"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> values separated by "|" </t></r></si><si><t>Column</t></si><si><t>Value</t></si><si><t>Class</t></si><si><t>Description</t></si><si><t>Remark</t></si><si><t>plant_name_id</t></si><si><t>chr</t></si><si><t>World Checklist of Vascular Plants (WCVP) identifier</t></si><si><t>ipni_id</t></si><si><t>taxon_rank</t></si><si><t>Convariety, Form, Genus, proles, Species, Subform, Subspecies, Subvariety, Variety</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The level in the taxonomic hierarchy where the taxon name fits. Some infraspecific names are unranked and will have no value in this column.  </t></si><si><t>taxon_status</t></si><si><t>family</t></si><si><t>The name of the family to which the taxon belongs. (The highest rank at which names are presented in WCVP).</t></si><si><t>genus_hybrid</t></si><si><t>+, ×</t></si><si><t>Indication of hybrid status at genus level: + indicates a graft-chimaera and × indicates a hybrid.</t></si><si><t>genus</t></si><si><t>The name of the genus to which the record refers.</t></si><si><t>species_hybrid</t></si><si><t>Indication of hybrid status at species level: + indicates a graft-chimaera and × indicates a hybrid.</t></si><si><t>species</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The species epithet which is combined with the genus name to make a binomial name for a species. Empty when the taxon name is at the rank of genus. </t></si><si><t>infraspecific_rank</t></si><si><t>agamosp., convar., ecas., f., grex, group, lusus, microf., microgene, micromorphe, modif., monstr., mut., nid, nothof., nothosubsp., nothovar., positio, proles, provar., psp., stirps, subf., sublusus, subproles, subsp., subspecioid, subvar., unterrasse, var.</t></si><si><t>The taxonomic rank of the infraspecific epithet. Empty where the taxon name is species rank or higher. For more information, see the International Code of Nomenclature for algae, fungi and plants:  https://www.iapt-taxon.org/nomen/main.php</t></si><si><t>infraspecies</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The infraspecific epithet which is combined with a binomial to make a trinomial name at infraspecific rank. Empty when taxon name is at species rank or higher. </t></si><si><t>parenthetical_author</t></si><si><t>primary_author</t></si><si><t>publication_author</t></si><si><t>place_of_publication</t></si><si><t>Abbreviated for brevity</t></si><si><t>volume_and_page</t></si><si><t>Not all volumes include issue number</t></si><si><t>first_published</t></si><si><t>nomenclatural_remarks</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Remarks on the nomenclature. </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Preceded by a comma and space (", ") for easy concatenation. </t></si><si><t>geographic_area</t></si><si><t>The geographic distribution of the taxon (for names of species rank or below): a generalised statement in narrative form.</t></si><si><t>See https://wcsp.science.kew.org/about.do#geography for details</t></si><si><t>lifeform_description</t></si><si><t>See https://wcsp.science.kew.org/about.do#lifeforms for a glossary of terms used</t></si><si><t>climate_description</t></si><si><t>Desert and Dry Shrubland, Desert or Dry Shrubland, Montane Tropical, Seasonally Dry Tropical, Subalpine or Subarctic, Subtropical, Subtropical and Tropical, Temperate, Temperate and Tropical, Wet Tropical</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Habitat type of the taxon, derived from published habitat information. </t></si><si><t>taxon_name</t></si><si><t>Concatenation of genus with species and, where applicable, infraspecific epithets to make a binomial or trinomial name.</t></si><si><t>taxon_authors</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">Concatenation of parenthetical and primary authors. Missing values indicate instances where authorship is unknown or non-applicable (e.g. autonyms). </t></si><si><t>accepted_plant_name_id</t></si><si><t>The ID of the accepted name of this taxon. Where the taxon_status is "Accepted", this will be identical to the plant_name_id value. May be empty if taxon status is unplaced, ilegitimate, or in some cases where the accepted name is not a vascular plant (e.g. a moss, alga or animal).</t></si><si><t>basionym_plant_name_id</t></si><si><t>homotypic_synonym</t></si><si><t>logical</t></si><si><t>The synonym type - TRUE if homotypic synonym, otherwise NA.</t></si><si><t>For more information, see the International Code of Nomenclature for algae, fungi and plants:  https://www.iapt-taxon.org/nomen/main.php</t></si><si><t>parent_plant_name_id</t></si><si><t>ID for the parent genus or parent species of an accepted species or infraspecific name. Empty for non accepted names or where the parent has not yet been calculated.</t></si><si><t>Metadata for file "checklist_distribution.txt"</t></si><si><t>WCVP identifier, corresponding to the field of the same name in checklist_names.txt</t></si><si><t>continent_code_l1</t></si><si><t>int</t></si><si><t>Numeric botanical continent code (TDWG Level 1)</t></si><si><t>continent</t></si><si><t>Botanical continent (TDWG Level 1)</t></si><si><t>See https://www.tdwg.org/standards/wgsrpd/  for details</t></si><si><t>region_code_l2</t></si><si><t>Numeric botanical region code (TDWG Level 2)</t></si><si><t>region</t></si><si><t>Botanical region (TDWG Level 2)</t></si><si><t>area_code_l3</t></si><si><t>Three letter botanical area code (TDWG Level 3)</t></si><si><t>area</t></si><si><t>Botanical area (TDWG Level 3)</t></si><si><t>introduced</t></si><si><t>0,1</t></si><si><t>Introduced status of the taxon: 0 if native, 1 if introduced</t></si><si><t>extinct</t></si><si><t>Local extinction status of the taxon: 0 if extant in location, 1 if extinct in region</t></si><si><t>location_doubtful</t></si><si><t>Doubtful status of taxon:  1 if doubtfully present, else 0</t></si><si><t>WCVP Dataset:</t></si><si><t>hybrid_formula</t></si><si><t>parents of hybrid</t></si><si><t>reviewed</t></si><si><t>Flag indicating whether the family to which the taxon belongs has been peer reviewed.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">identifier required to look up the name directly in Plants of the World Online (Powo) </t></si><si><t>powo_id</t></si><si><t>To cite WCVP</t></si><si><t>For further information</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="11"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Calibri"/><family val="2"/><scheme val="minor"/></rPr><t>Note:</t></r><r><rPr><sz val="11"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Calibri"/><family val="2"/><scheme val="minor"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve"> Fields separated by '|' and encoding = "UTF-8"</t></r></si><si><t>replaced_synonym_author</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">ID of the original name that taxon_name was derived from. If there is a parenthetical author it is a basionym. If there is a replaced synonym author it is a replaced synonym. If empty there have been no name changes. </t></si><si><t>The author or authors responsible for publication of the replaced synonym. Empty when the name is not a replacement name based on another name.</t></si><si><t>Govaerts, R., Nic Lughadha, E. et al. The World Checklist of Vascular Plants, a continuously updated resource for exploring global plant diversity. Sci Data 8, 215 (2021). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-021-00997-6</t></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="11"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Calibri"/><family val="2"/><scheme val="minor"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">To read into R:  </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="11"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Calibri"/><family val="2"/><scheme val="minor"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">    </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="11"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Consolas"/><family val="3"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">read.table("wcvp_names.csv", sep="|", header=TRUE, quote = "", fill=TRUE, encoding = "UTF-8") </t></r></si><si><r><rPr><b/><sz val="11"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Calibri"/><family val="2"/><scheme val="minor"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">To read into R:  </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="11"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Calibri"/><family val="2"/><scheme val="minor"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">    </t></r><r><rPr><sz val="11"/><color theme="1"/><rFont val="Consolas"/><family val="3"/></rPr><t xml:space="preserve">read.table("wcvp_distribution.csv", sep="|", header=TRUE, quote = "", fill=TRUE, encoding = "UTF-8") </t></r></si><si><t>plant_locality_id</t></si><si><t>Sequential number</t></si><si><t>Ignore if using own primary key</t></si><si><t>International Plant Name Index (IPNI) identifier. Missing values indicate that the name has not been matched with a name in IPNI or is missing from IPNI.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The author of the basionym. Empty when there is no basionym. </t></si><si><t>The author or authors who published the scientific name. Missing values indicate instances where authorship is non-applicable (i.e. autonyms) or unknown.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The author or authors of the book where the scientific name is first published when different from the primary author. Missing values indicate instances where the primary author is also the author of the book or non-applicable (i.e. autonyms). </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The journal, book or other publication in which the taxon name was effectively published. Missing values indicate instances where publication details are unknown or non-applicable (i.e. autonyms). </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The volume and page numbers of the original publication of the taxon name, where "5(6): 36" is volume 5, issue 6, page 36. Missing values indicate instances where publication details are unknown or non-applicable (i.e. autonyms). </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The year of publication of the name, enclosed in parentheses. Missing values indicate instances where publication details are unknown or non-applicable (i.e. autonyms). </t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">The lifeform (or lifeforms) of the taxon. Terms refer to a modified verison of the Raunkiær system. Missing values if unknown. </t></si><si><t>Version "12"</t></si><si><t>Extracted: 28/09/2023</t></si><si><t>Table: 1,422,868 rows and 31 columns</t></si><si><t>Table: 1,962,423 rows and 11 columns</t></si><si><t>Accepted, Artificial Hybrid, Illegitimate, Invalid, Local Biotype, Misapplied, Orthographic, Synonym, Unplaced, Provisionally Accepted</t></si><si><t>Indication of nomenclatural status and taxonomic opinion re the name: see details in main text. Names with status ‘Provisionally Accepted’ are unplaced names that have synonyms, following the GBIF classification and only used within the Darwin Core Archive downlaod.</t></si><si><t>Govaerts R (ed.). 2023. WCVP: World Checklist of Vascular Plants. Facilitated by the Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew. [WWW document] URL https://doi.org/10.34885/jdh2-dr22 [accessed 28 September 2023].</t></si></sst>